to jump at the uh
from year to year at a transfer court.
>> Yeah, it's a good question. I think like
overall everybody makes their own
decision, you know, whether that's
that's
their own reasons, their personal
reasons. So, it's not really a matter of
judging whether you're transferring or
not. It's more a matter of giving him
the credit to staying loyal to the
school and really wanted to uh give back
to the school that gave him a chance uh
when he didn't really have any offers.
now that he was producing and he could
have just uh left. And he said something
to me that really stuck out. He said
something along the lines of, you know,
the long-term financials or the big, you
know, uh financial gains will come when
I make it to the NFL. And that's kind of
was his mindset. So, just it's just a
testament to him and his maturity and
his process and all that.
>> It's obviously not a secret like not all
college programs are created equal.
There's the FBS, the FCS, whatever. the
the MAC schools aren't considered like
the premier programs, but you know,
back-to-back years now where you took
you're taking Emanuel McNeil Warren out
to obviously Har Fannon last year. How
what what are the things that you like
see or can use to know like this isn't
just a guy who's doing it in the MAC or
at a smaller level. This is a guy that
we know can play with the other players
in the in the higher up leagues or in
the NFL and actually make it. Um,
I like that you asked that question
because that's a conversation we had uh
a lot when I was working in Philly uh
under obviously Howie Roseman and Tom
Dono who'd been a GM obviously been in
the league for a long time and when we
talk about level edition of course you
have to take it into account in your in
your eval evaluation process but he'd
say they play against who they got to
play and at some point that's what we
need to evaluate and that's our job to
project that based on the tools that
they have their athletic profile and how
we think that's going to project again
against against NFL talent and at every
level it is a projection now maybe
easier to make in some programs others
but that's our job and that's that's
what we um spend a ton of time doing
watching the tape um but at the end of
the day who they play against as tape we
had to watch and that's our job to
project
>> Andrew had mentioned that you know with
that for more teams playing three safety
that position is sort of gaining in
profile is is that position becoming
more and more important as far as like
you know obviously we always talk edge
rushers and corners and things like
that. The safety starting to kind of
reach that level.
>> I think at the end of the day,
regardless of position, of course
there's premium premium position and
those types of things, but at the end of
the day, like any position that's going
to make an impact, take the ball away
from for us, like take it away, uh give
it back to our offense. Those became
playmakers and that's what we're trying
to add at every position. Eman brings
that.
>> The draft is part skill, part luck. How
do you improve the the skill part of it?
I think it goes back to your process. It
goes back to um the the the ton of film
that we watch. That's where it starts.
Um and that years of years of work from
our aeros scouts, that's really like the
ground the ground level, the starting
point. And then you add all the other
piece of information that you gather
through your process, whether that's the
medical information, your character,
your testing numbers, um the
interactions you've had with them, what
the coaches think of them. And as to me,
your process gets better better at
aggregating all that information and
make good decisions, sound decisions.
Um, again, good player, good person. Uh,
those are things we can't miss on.
>> Couple more. This is a player that was
projected by many amateurs as a first
round pick.
Do you think he fell farther than you
expected or is this the range that you
guys projected?
>> We're just happy with where we took him.
I mean, where he was on our board for
us, it was a no-brainer to get up and
get him based on what we think he's
going to bring bring to our program. So,
at that point for us is just really
excited about where we got him.
>> Point for a second. How much does
experience help just being able to go
through multiple drafts and learn from
how you how you've done in the past?
>> I think
that you have around yourself that you
surround yourself with Andrew has done
an excellent job of having a staff that
is uh in terms of skill experience. I
mean just at the table right now
upstairs we have Tom Telesco and Chris
Bolan. Uh you have Jimmy Ray who's done
that for decades. So just the level of
experience that we have in advising um
in advising our
is just is just diverse and excellent.
So I think that helps that definitely
helps our process and in making good
decisions when the time comes.
>> Thank you guys.